Register of the Trotsky collection, 1917-1995
Hoover Institution Archives
- LEON TROTSKY CORRESPONDENCE, 1926-1940. (Box 9-13)
  - Outgoing
    - Maitland, Frank, 1938 April 15 (Folder 59)
    - Malamuth, Charles
      - 1939 October 21 (Folder 60)
      - 1940 March 19 (Folder 61)
    - Mejsnar, I., 1938 June 1 (Folder 62)
    - Milton, Harry, 1937 November 6 (Folder 63)
    - Moustakis, Chris, 1940 August 17 (Folder 64)
    - Muralov, Nikolai, 1928 September 11 (Folder 65)
    - Muste, A. J., 1936 February 8 (Folder 66)
    - Naville, Pierre
      - 1937 February 25 (Folder 67)
      - 1938 May 10 (Folder 68)
    - Nin, Andres, 1931 September 1 (Folder 69)
    - Novack, George
      - 1937
        - March 9 (Folder 70-71)
        - August 31 (Folder 72)
        - September 25 (Folder 73)
      - 1939 December 28 (Folder 74)
      - 1940 January 16 (Folder 75)
    - Ordzhonikidze, Grigorii, 1927
      - June 28 (Folder 76)
      - July 25 (Folder 77)
      - August 1 (Folder 78)
    - Parti Ouvrier Internationaliste (France), 1936
      - June 19 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - June 21 (Folder 2)
      - July 11 (Folder 3)
    - Preobrazhenskii, Evgenii, 1928 March-April (Folder 4)
    - Reiss, Else, 1937 October 13 (Folder 5)
    - Revolutionair Socialistische Arbeiders Partij (Netherlands), 1936 July 16 (Folder 6)
    - Rous, Jean, 1935 July 30 (Folder 7)
    - Schlamm, Willi, 1935 December 24 (Folder 8)
    - Schultz, Henry, 1940 August 20 (Folder 9)
    - Serebriakov, Leonid, 1927 September 12 (Folder 10)
    - Shachtman, Max
      - 1931
        - May 23 (Folder 11)
        - July 1 (Folder 12)
      - 1939
        - November 6 (Folder 13)
        - Sneevliet, Henk, December 20 (Folder 14)
      - 1934 March 17 (Folder 15)
      - 1935 November 5 (Folder 16)
      - 1937 December 2 (Folder 17)
    - Socialist Appeal Association, 1937 September 30 (Folder 18)
    - Socialist Lawyers' Front, 1937 March 15 (Folder 19)
    - Socialist Workers Party
      - 1937
        - December 30 (Folder 20)
        - December 31 (Folder 21)
      - 1938
        - February 10 (Folder 22)
        - February 22 (Folder 23)
        - May 21 (Folder 24)
      - 1939
        - January 1 (Folder 25)
        - April 18 (Folder 26)
        - April 22 (Folder 27)
        - October 12 (Folder 28)
        - November 28 (Folder 29)
        - December 26 (Folder 30)
        - December 27 (Folder 31)
      - 1940
        - January 3 (Folder 32)
        - January 4 (Folder 33)
        - February 20 (Folder 34)
        - February 21 (Folder 35)
        - February 23 (Folder 36)
        - March 21 (Folder 37)
        - August 13 (Folder 38)
    - Soviet Union. Tsentral'nyi Ispolnitel'nyi Komitet, 1927 November 15 (Folder 39)
    - Stanley, Sherman, 1939 October 8 (Folder 40)
    - Sumner, Charles, 1938 April 15 (Folder 41)
    - TSK VKP(b) Politbiuro, 1927
      - September 6 (Folder 42)
      - September 12 (Folder 43)
      - October 1 (Folder 44)
      - November 9 (Folder 45)
    - Thomas, Wendelin, 1938 January 17 (Folder 46)
    - Treint, Albert, 1931 September 13 (Folder 47)
    - Unidentified
      - Undated (Folder 48)
      - 1928 June 2 (Folder 49)
      - 1936 January 28 (Folder 50)
      - 1938 December 22 (Folder 51)
      - 1939 January 31 (Folder 52)
    - United States. Congress. House. Committee on Un-American Activities, 1939 October 12 (Folder 53)
    - Vardin, 1927 April 26 (Folder 54)
    - Vazquez, Federico, 1933 April 12 (Folder 55)
    - Vereecken, Georges, 1935 November 18 (Folder 56)
    - Vsesoiuznaia Kommunisticheskaia Partiia (bol'shevikov) Tsentral'naia Kontrol'naia Komissiia, 1927
      - January 26 (Folder 57)
      - August 27 (Folder 58)
    - Vsesoiuznaia Kommunisticheskaia Partiia (bol'shevikov) Tsentral'nyi Komitet. See TSK VKP(b)
    - Walker, Charles R.
      - 1937
        - July 6 (Folder 59)
        - September 17 (Folder 60)
      - 1938 February 10 (Folder 61)
    - Wasserman, Jac
      - 1937 November 14 (Folder 62)
      - 1938 June 14 (Folder 63)
    - Weber, Jack, 1937 December 1 (Folder 64)
    - Weber, Sara
      - 1937
        - August 21 (Folder 65)
        - September 18 (Folder 66)
        - October 4 (Folder 67)
      - 1938 April 26 (Folder 68)
    - Wechsler, Abraham, 1940 August 3 (Folder 69)
    - Weisbord, Albert, 1932 May 22 (Folder 70)
    - Wolf, Erwin, 1936
      - July 27 (Folder 71)
      - July 29 (Folder 72)
      - October 4 (Folder 73)
    - Workers Party of the U.S., 1935
      - August 11 (Folder 74)
      - August 12 (Folder 75)
      - August 13 (Folder 76)
    - Wright, John G.
      - 1933 November 21 (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - 1937
        - February 20 (Folder 2)
        - April 28 (Folder 3)
        - April 29 (Folder 4)
        - May 21 (Folder 5)
        - June 3 (Folder 6)
        - June 11 (Folder 7)
        - August 21 (Folder 8)
        - November 6 (Folder 9)
      - 1938
        - February 5 (Folder 10)
        - April 5 (Folder 11)
        - September 12 (Folder 12)
        - October 17 (Folder 13)
      - 1939
        - January 21 (Folder 14)
        - January 31 (Folder 15)
        - February 1 (Folder 16)
        - February 10 (Folder 17)
        - February 14 (Folder 18)
        - March 20 (Folder 19)
        - March 29 (Folder 20)
        - September 28 (Folder 21)
        - November 11 (Folder 22)
        - December 19 (Folder 23)
      - (ca.) Undated, 1939-1940 (Folder 24)
      - 1940
        - January 7 (Folder 25)
        - January 10 (Folder 26)
        - January 13 (Folder 27)
        - January 25 (Folder 28)
        - February 7 (Folder 29)
        - March 4 (Folder 30)
        - April 6 (Folder 31)
        - April 20 (Folder 32)
        - April 24 (Folder 33)
        - April 26 (Folder 34)
        - May 2 (Folder 35)
        - July 17 (Folder 36)
        - July 27 (Folder 37)
  - Incoming
    - Aftenposten (Oslo), Includes translations of news dispatches, 1937-1938. (Folder 38)
    - Agence Telegraphique Juive, 1937 (Folder 39)
    - Anonymous, Includes related letter by Albert Goldman, 1938. (Folder 40)
    - Carolina Political Union, 1937 (Folder 41)
    - Carter, Joseph, 1937 (Folder 42)
    - Communist League of America, 1933 (Folder 43)
    - Dobbs, Farrell, 1940 (Folder 44)
    - Frankel, Jan, 1937 (Folder 45)
    - Glass, C. Frank, 1935 (Folder 46)
    - Glotzer, Albert, 1937 (Folder 47)
    - Goldman, Albert, 1939-1940 (Folder 48)
    - Hansen, Joseph, 1939-1940 (Folder 49)
    - Hansen, Reba, 1940 (Folder 50)
    - Held, Walter, 1933-1937 (Folder 51)
    - Holm og Rode (Law firm), 1938 (Folder 52)
    - Isaacs, Harold R., ca. 1934-1938 (Folder 53)
    - Karsner, Rose, 1940 (Folder 54)
    - Landau, Kurt, 1930 (Folder 55)
    - La Lutte Group (Vietnam), 1939 (Folder 56)
    - Maitland, Frank, 1938 (Folder 57)
    - Martin, Jeanne, 1938 (Folder 58)
    - Moguel Traconis, Manuel, 1937 (Folder 59)
    - El Nacional (Mexico City), 1937 (Folder 60)
    - New York Public Library, 1940 (Folder 61)
    - Novack, George, 1937 (Folder 62)
    - Orlov, Aleksandr, 1938 (Folder 63)
    - Paris-Soir, 1937 (Folder 64)
    - Pickens, William, 1937 (Folder 65)
    - Rosmer, Alfred, 1930 (Folder 66)
    - Sabath, A. J., 1939 (Folder 67)
    - Selander, Ted, 1937 (Folder 68)
    - Shachtman, Max, 1936-1939 (Folder 69)
    - Stanford University, 1940 (Folder 70)
    - Swabeck, Arne, 1933 (Folder 71)
    - Unidentified, 1938 (Folder 72)
    - United States. Congress. House. Committee on Un-American Activities, 1939 (Folder 73)
    - Wolf, Erwin, 1937 (Folder 74)
    - Wright, John G., 1933-1940. See also LEON TROTSKY SPEECHES AND WRITINGS/ Stalin (Folder 75)
- LEON TROTSKY SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1907-1940. (Box 14-22)
  Speeches and writings by Leon Trotsky, arranged chronologically by date of composition. Date and source of first publication (including mimeographed internal bulletins) is also given. Items are cited by original titles whenever possible. See also V. I. LENIN FILE/Miscellany/Trotsky, Leon
  - General. Selected writings, 1930-1940, published in booklet form as Por los Estados Unidos Socialistas de America Latina (Buenos Aires, Printed copy (in Spanish), 1961). (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Tuda i obratno, Published in St. Petersburg, 1907
    - Printed copy (in English), entitled My Flight from Siberia (Berlin, 1923) (Folder 2)
    - Printed copy (in English), entitled My Flight from Siberia (New York, 1925) (Folder 3)
  - "Intelligentsiia i sotsializm," 1910 November. Published in Sovremennyi mir (1910 November). Printed copies in pamphlet form (in English), entitled The Intelligentsia and Socialism (London, 1966, 1974) (Folder 4)
  - Open letter to Jules Guesde, 1916 October 11. Published in La Vie ouvriere (1916). Printed copy in pamphlet form (in English), entitled Against Social-Patriotism (Colombo, 1952) (Folder 5)
  - "Tainye dogovory i tainaia diplomatiia," 1917 November 9. Published in Izvestiia (1917 November 10). Printed copy (in English), included in pamphlet Full Texts of Secret Treaties (New York, 1918) (Folder 6)
  - Interview with Edward Alsworth Ross, 1917 December. Published in The Independent (1918 March 9). Printed transcript (in English, in The Independent (Folder 7)
  - Istoriia oktiabr'skoi revoliutsii, Published in 1918
    - Printed copy (in Russian), entitled K istorii oktiabr'skoi revoliutsii (New York, 1919) (Folder 8)
    - Printed copy (in English), entitled From October to Brest-Litovsk (New York, 1919) (Folder 9)
  - Our Revolution, 1918. Published in New York, 1918. Printed copy of excerpts in pamphlet form (in English), entitled 1905: Before and After (Colombo, 1953) (Folder 10)
  - What Is a Peace Programme? Published in Petrograd and San Francisco, 1918. Printed copy (in English, Colombo, 1956) (Folder 11)
  - "Slovo russkim rabochim i krestianam o nashakh druz'iakh i vragakh i o tom, kak uberech' i uprochit' Sovetskuiu Respubliku," speech, 1918 April 14. Published as pamphlet with same title (Moscow, 1918). Printed copy in pamphlet form (in English), entitled A Paradise in This World (Colombo, 1957) (Folder 12)
  - "Karl Libknekht i Roza Liuksemburg," eulogy, Petrograd, 1919 January 18. Published as pamphlet with same title (Petrograd, 1919). Printed copy in pamphlet form (in English), entitled Martyrs of the Third International: Karl Liebknecht, Rosa Luxemburg (London, 1971). Also includes "Luxemburg and the Fourth International", (1935 June 24) (Folder 13)
  - "Beglye mysli o Plekhanove," 1919 March 18. Published in Pod znanemen marksizma (1922). Printed copy in pamphlet form (in English), entitled George Valentinovich Plekhanov (Colombo, 1949) (Folder 14)
  - Mezhdu imperializmom i revoliutsiei, 1922. Published in Moscow, 1922. Printed copy (in English), entitled Between Red and White (London (Folder 15)
  - 1905, Published in Moscow, 1922. Printed copy (in Russian, Moscow, 1925) (Folder 16)
  - Voina i revoliutsiia, 1922. Published in Petrograd, Printed copy (in Russian, Moscow and Petrograd, 1924), 1922-1923.
    - Volume I (Folder 17)
    - Volume II (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Speech, Kommunisticheskii Soiuz Molodezhy congress, 1922 October 11. Published in Trud (1922 October 12). Printed copy in pamphlet form (in English), entitled The Position of the Republic and the Tasks of Young Workers (London, 1972) (Folder 2)
  - Voprosy byta, Published in Moscow, 1923. Printed copy (in Russian, Moscow, 1925) (Folder 3)
  - O Lenine, Published in Moscow, 1924
    - Printed copy (in Russian, Moscow, 1924) (Folder 4)
    - Printed copy of excerpts in pamphlet form (in English), entitled Lenin (Colombo, 1951) (Folder 5)
  - "Lenina net!" 1924 January 22. Published in Izvestiia (1924 January 24). Printed copy in pamphlet form (in Turkmen), entitled Lenin yok! Yakdir indi Lenin! (Tashkent (Folder 6)
  - "Molodezh, uchis' politike!" speech, 1924 April 29. Published in Kommunisticheskii Internatsional (1924 May-June). Printed copy in pamphlet form (in English), entitled The Fight for Marxism (London, 1966). Also includes English versions of "Leninizm i rabochie kluby" and speech on Soviet Georgia (1926 February 25), (1924 July 17) (Folder 7)
  - "Voprosy grazhdanskoi voiny," speech, Moscow, 1924 July 29. Published in Izvestiia (1924 August 26-28). Mimeograph copy (incomplete, in English, in Free Expressio^*n\*, 1945 January), and printed copy (in French, in Initiative socialiste, 1968 June) (Folder 8)
  - "Kabardino-Balkarskaia avtonomnaia oblast' i ee zadachi," speech, Nalchik, 1924 September 22. Published in Izvestiia (1924 October 17). Printed copy in pamphlet form (in Karandaish), entitled Qabarty byla malqarny aftonomny oblastary byla any ne dat eterge bulganyny haqqyndar (Moscow, 1925) (Folder 9)
  - Offer of resignation from Revoliutsionnyi Voennyi Sovet Respubliki, 1925 January 15. Published in Izvestiia (1925 January 20). Printed copy in pamphlet form (in Russian), entitled Otstavka Trotskogo (Berlin, ca. 1925) (Folder 10)
  - "D. I. Mendeleev i marksizm," speech, 1925 September 17. Published in Ekonomicheskaia zhizn' (1925 September 18-29). Printed copy in pamphlet form (in English), entitled Marxism and Science (Colombo, 1949) (Folder 11)
  - "Kultura i sotsializm," speech, Moscow, 1926 February 3. Published in Krasnaia nov (1926). Printed copy in pamphlet form (in English), entitled Culture and Socialism, and a Manifesto: Towards a Free Revolutionary Art (London, 1975). Includes "Manifesto: Toward a Free Revolutionary Art", (1938 July 25) (Folder 12)
  - "Radio, nauka, tekhnika i obshchestvo," speech, 1926 March 1. Published in Krasnaia nov (1927). Printed copy in pamphlet form (in English), entitled Radio, Science, Technique and Society (London, 1974) (Folder 13)
  - "Voprosy nashei politiki v otnoshenii Kitaia i Iaponii," 1926 March 25. Published in Leon Trotsky on China (New York, Typescript (in Russian), 1976). (Folder 14)
  - "Popravki k proektu rezoliutsii T. Rykova o khoziaistvennom polozhenii SSSR," 1926 April 12. Published in Hapoel Hatzair Typescript (in Russian) (Folder 15)
  - "Voprosy britanskogo rabochego dvizheniia," 1926 May 19. Published in Pravda Typescript of excerpts (in Russian), (1926 May 25-26). (Folder 16)
  - "Chto takoe 'demokratiia'?" 1926 June 6. Published in The Challenge of the Left Opposition, 1926-27 (New York, Typescript of excerpts (in Russian), 1980). (Folder 17)
  - "O ravenstve," 1926 July 11. Published in The Challenge of the Left Opposition, 1926-27 (New York, Typescript (in Russian), 1980). (Folder 18)
  - Declaration to TSK VKP(b) Politbiuro, Typescript (in Russian), 1926 August 13. (Folder 19)
  - Answers to questions on the Russian opposition, 1926 September. Published in The New International Typescript (in Russian), (1938 May). (Folder 20)
  - Theses for 15th Conference, Vsesoiuznaia Kommunisticheskaia Partiia (bol'shevikov), Typescript of excerpts (in Russian), 1926 September 19. (Folder 21)
  - "Iz dnevnika," 1926 November 26. Published in The Age of Permanent Revolution (New York, Typescript of excerpts (in Russian), 1964). (Folder 22)
  - "Voprosy Kominterna v delegatsiiu VKP(b)," 1927 January 18. Published in The Challenge of the Left Opposition, 1926-27 (New York, Typescript (in Russian), 1980). (Folder 23)
  - "Tekushchii moment," 1927 February 19. Published in Dnevniki i pis'ma (Tenafly, N.J., Typescript of excerpts (in Russian), 1986). (Folder 24)
  - Memorandum to TSK VKP(b), 1927 February 21. Published in The Challenge of the Left Opposition, 1926-27 (New York, Typescript (in Russian), 1980). (Folder 25)
  - "Klassovye otnosheniia kitaiskoi revoliutsii," 1927 April 3. Published in The New International Typescript (in Russian), (1938 March-April). (Folder 26)
  - "Po lichnomu voprosu," 1927 April 14. Published in Portrety (Benson, Vt., Typescript (in Russian), 1984). (Folder 27)
  - "Ob Anglo-Russkom Komitete," Typescript of excerpts (in Russian), 1927 April 15. (Folder 28)
  - "O lozunge sovetov v Kitae," 1927 April 16. Published in Leon Trotsky on China (New York, Typescript of excerpts (in Russian), 1976). (Folder 29)
  - "O nashei zavisimosti ot mirovogo rynka," Typescript (in Russian), 1927 April 16. (Folder 30)
  - "Druzhestvennyi obmen portretami Stalina i Chan-Kai-Shi," 1927 April 18. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii Typescript (in Russian), (1932 July). (Folder 31)
  - "Bor'ba za mir i Anglo-Russkii Komitet," 1927 May 16. Published in Der Kampf um die Kommunistische Internationale (Berlin, Typescript (in Russian) (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Protest to TSK VKP(b) Politbiuro and Vsesoiuznaia Kommunisticheskaia Partiia (bol'shevikov) Tsentral'naia Kontrol'naia Komissiia, 1927 May 16. Published in Leon Trotsky on China (New York, Typescript of excerpts (in Russian), 1976). (Folder 2)
  - First speech on Chinese question, Communist International Executive Committee Presidium, 1927 May 24. Published in Problems of the Chinese Revolution (New York, Typescript (in Russian), 1932). (Folder 3)
  - Second speech on Chinese question, Communist International Executive Committee Presidium, 1927 May 24. Published in Der Kampf um die Kommunistische Internationale (Berlin, Typescript (in Russian) (Folder 4)
  - "Dva slova ob armii," Typescript (in Russian), 1927 July. (Folder 5)
  - Protest to Vserossiiskii Soiuz Rabochikh Metallistov, 1927 July 1. Published in The Challenge of the Left Opposition, 1926-27 (New York, Typescript (in Russian), 1980). (Folder 6)
  - Replies to questions, joint plenum, TSK VKP(b) and Vsesoiuznaia Kommunisticheskaia Partiia (bol'shevikov) Tsentral'naia Kontrol'naia Komissiia, Typescript (in Russian), 1927 August. (Folder 7)
  - "Termidor," 1927 August. Published in The Challenge of the Left Opposition, 1926-27 (New York, Typescript (in Russian), 1980). (Folder 8)
  - "Klemanso," Typescript (in Russian), 1927 August 2. (Folder 9)
  - Speech, joint plenum, TSK VKP(b) and Vsesoiuznaia Kommunisticheskaia Partiia (bol'shevikov) Tsentral'naia Kontrol'naia Komissiia, 1927 August 6. Published in The Challenge of the Left Opposition, 1926-27 (New York, Typescript (in Russian), 1980). (Folder 10)
  - "Chego zhdali i chto poluchili?" 1927 September 23. Published in The New International Typescript (in Russian), (1934 September-October). (Folder 11)
  - "'Tezis o Klemanso' i rezhim v partii," 1927 September 24. Published in The New International Typescript (in Russian), (1934 July). (Folder 12)
  - Speech to Communist International Executive Committee Presidium, 1927 September 27. Published in Leon Trotsky on China (New York, Typescript of excerpts (in Russian), 1976). (Folder 13)
  - "Ko vsem chlenam partii," 1927 October 4. Published in The New International Typescript (in Russian), (1934 November). (Folder 14)
  - Speech, 1927 October 15. Published in Fahne des Kommunismus Typescript (in Russian), (1927 November 11). (Folder 15)
  - Speech to TSK VKP(b), 1927 October 3. Published in Pravda Typescript of excerpts (in Russian), (1927 November 2). (Folder 16)
  - "Posle slovesnogo zigzaga vlevo, glubokii sdvig vpravo," 1927 November 8. Published in The Challenge of the Left Opposition, 1926-27 (New York, Typescript (in Russian), 1980). (Folder 17)
  - "Zaiavlenie oppozitsii i polozhenie v partii," 1927 November 20. Published in The Challenge of the Left Opposition, 1926-27 (New York, Typescript (in Russian), 1980). (Folder 18)
  - "Na novom etape," 1927 December 15. Published in Fahne des Kommunismus Typescript (in Russian), (1928 December 21-28). (Folder 19)
  - The Real Situation in Russia, 1928. Published in New York, 1928. Printed copy of excerpts in pamphlet form (in Turkish), entitled Rusyada hakiki vaziyet (Berlin, 1929) (Folder 20)
  - "The Draft Program of the Communist International," Published in booklet form under same title (New York, 1929). Typescript of fragments (in English), 1928 June 28. (Folder 21)
  - "K voprosu o proiskhozhdenii legendy o 'trotskizme'," 1928 July 12. Published in Stalinskaia shkola falsifikatsii (Berlin, Typescript (in Russian), 1932). (Folder 22)
  - "Kto rukovodit nyne Kominternom?" 1928 September. Published in Fahne des Kommunismus Typescript (in Russian), (1929 May 17-June 28). (Folder 23)
  - "Beseda na chistotu s dobrozhelatel'nym partiitsem," 1928 September 12. Published in La Revolution defiguree (Paris, Typescript (in Russian), 1929). (Folder 24)
  - Circular letter, 1928 October 21. Published in Fahne des Kommunismus Typescript (in Russian), (1929 January 4). (Folder 25)
  - "V chem raznoglasiia s D. Ts. (Gruppa 15)," 1928 November 11. Published in Fahne des Kommunismus Typescript (in Russian), (1929 January 25). (Folder 26)
  - "Na zloby dnia," 1928 December. Published in The Challenge of the Left Opposition, 1928-29 (New York, Typescript (in Russian), 1981). (Folder 27)
  - Chto i kak proizoshlo? Published in Paris, 1929. Printed copy (in Russian, Paris, 1929) (Folder 28)
  - "Zhalkii dokument," Published in leaflet form under same title (Constantinople, 1929). Printed copy (in Russian, Constantinople, 1929), 1929 July 27. (Folder 29)
  - "Concerning the Communication of the German National Committee of " ca. 1930-1931. Typescript (in English), Dec. 28, 1930 (Folder 30)
  - "Pamiati druga: nad svezhei mogiloi Kote Tsintsadze," 1931 January 7. Published in La Verite Typescript (in English). Includes typescripts of related articles of uncertain authorship, (1931 January 16). (Folder 31)
  - "Uber die Bordigisten: Kritische Bemerkungen anlasslich der Resolution der Gruppe Prometheo uber den Kampf fur demokratische Losungen," 1931 January 15. Published in Bulletin international de l'Opposition Communiste de Gauche (1932 June). Mimeograph copy (in French). Also includes French versions of message to conference of the International Left Opposition Spanish Section (1932 March 7), and of greetings to Unzer Kamf, (1932 May 9) (Folder 32)
  - "The Crisis in the German Left Opposition," 1931 February 17. Published in Bulletin international de l'Opposition Communiste de Gauche Typed copy (in English), (1931 April). (Folder 33)
  - Circular letter, 1931 May 5. Published in Mitteilungsblatt der Reichsleitung der Linken Opposition der KPD (Bolschewiki-Leninisten) Typescript (in German), (1931 June). (Folder 34)
  - "Voprosy ispanskoi revoliutsii izo dnia v den'," 1931 July 8. Published in Internationales Bulletin der Kommunistischen Links-Opposition Mimeograph copy (in German), (1931 August). (Folder 35)
  - "A Few Remarks Apropos the Internal Differences and Friction in the Ligue (France)," 1931 September 25. Published in Bulletin interieur de la Ligue Communiste Typed copy (in English), (1931 October). (Folder 36)
  - "Why Russia Dare Not Fight Japan," 1931 November 30. Published in Liberty (1932 February 27). Printed copy (in English, in Liberty (Folder 37)
  - "Documentary Material for Discussion," 1931-1932. Published in Internal Bulletin of the Communist League of America Typed copy (in English), (1932 July). (Folder 38)
  - Nemetskaia revoliutsiia i stalinskaia biurokratiia, Published in Berlin, 1932
    - Typescript (incomplete, in Russian) (Folder 39)
    - Printed copy (in Russian, Berlin, 1932) (Folder 40)
  - "Otkrytoe pis'mo Prezidiumu TSIKa Soiuza SSSR," 1932 March 1. Published in Biulleten' oppozitsii (1932 March). Printed copy in pamphlet form (in Yiddish), entitled An ofener Briv tsum Prezidium fun Tsentraln Oisfir Komitet fun Sovetn Farband (New York (Folder 41)
  - "The Labor Party Question in the United States," 1932 May 19. Published in The Militant Typed copy (in English), (1932 June 11). (Folder 42)
  - Open letter to Zurich workers, 1932 June 25. Published in Der Bolschewik Typescript (in Russian), (1932 June-July). (Folder 43)
  - "Krestianskaia voina v Kitae i proletariat," 1932 September 22. Published in Bulletin of Marxist Studies Typed copy (in English), (1932 August). (Folder 44)